[
    {
        "question": "On which continent did the Boer War take place?",
        "answer": "Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2021, a team of mountain climbers completed to first winter ascent of which mountain?",
        "answer": "K2 -- On January 16, 2021, a team of climbers became the first to do what climbers had been trying for more than three decades."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Royal Greenhouses of Laeken are located in which European country?",
        "answer": "Belgium -- Located in Brussels, they were a 19th-century project designed for King Leopold II to complement the Castle of Laeken."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is home to the world`s longest roller coaster?",
        "answer": "Japan -- The Steel Dragon 2000 is 1.54 miles long, and it climbs up to speeds of 95 miles per hour and features a 307-foot drop."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Mexican dish`s name translates to `seasoned with chili`?",
        "answer": "Enchilada -- It consists of rolled corn or flour tortillas filled with beans, meat, cheese, and vegetables and covered in sauce."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Hawaiian island is nicknamed `Pineapple Island`?",
        "answer": "Lanai -- For about 70 years, Lanai was home to one of the world`s largest pineapple plantations, earning its nickname."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only country with Catalan as an official national language?",
        "answer": "Andorra -- It is an unofficial Romance language spoken by about 10 million people across parts of Spain, France, and Italy."
    },
    {
        "question": "What country was called the Gold Coast prior to its 1957 independence?",
        "answer": "Ghana"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US city would you find the fashionable Dupont Circle neighborhood?",
        "answer": "Washington, D.C."
    },
    {
        "question": "What Manhattan intersection was America`s first transfer circle?",
        "answer": "Columbus Circle"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Place de l`Etoile is the traffic circle that surrounds what landmark?",
        "answer": "The Arc de Triomphe"
    },
    {
        "question": "The former penal colony of Devil`s Island is located off the coast of what country?",
        "answer": "French Guiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Blue Ridge peak in North Carolina is the highest point east of the Mississippi?",
        "answer": "Mount Mitchell"
    },
    {
        "question": "Strine is the vernacular language spoken in which country?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rioja wine comes from which country?",
        "answer": "Spain "
    },
    {
        "question": "Frankfort is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "Kentucky"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what modern day country was Dalmatia located?",
        "answer": "Croatia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What islands are home to most of the world`s blue-footed boobies?",
        "answer": "The Galapagos Islands"
    },
    {
        "question": "Israel is name for the Old Testament patriarch born with what name?",
        "answer": "Jacob"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is called, in its native language, `Bharat`, after its legendary founder?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is named for the founder of the `Friars Preachers` religious order?",
        "answer": "The Dominican Republic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation is named for the Hapsburg king of Spain from 1556 to 1598?",
        "answer": "The Philippines"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the largest of the Canary Islands? ",
        "answer": "Tenerife"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the highest peak in the Appalachian range?",
        "answer": "Mount Mitchell"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country covers an entire continent?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What island is Tokyo located on?",
        "answer": "Honshu"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which English county is Charnwood Forest located?",
        "answer": "Leicestershire"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Toronto street was once thought to be the world`s longest street?",
        "answer": "Yonge"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Canada`s motto?",
        "answer": "From Sea to Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the last Province or Territory that joined Canada?",
        "answer": "Nunavut"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did the last Province or Territory join Canada?",
        "answer": "1999"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Canadian city would you find the largest mall in North America?",
        "answer": "Edmonton"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which region of Canada would you find Canada`s Technology Triangle?",
        "answer": "Waterloo Region"
    },
    {
        "question": "What European art museum has a glass pyramid in its courtyard?",
        "answer": "The Louvre"
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of stone is the Taj Mahal made of?",
        "answer": "Marble"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US president on Mount Rushmore has a mustache?",
        "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Angel Falls, the highest waterfall in the world, is located in what country?",
        "answer": "Venezuela"
    },
    {
        "question": "`The Running of the Bulls` event is held in what Spanish city?",
        "answer": "Pamplona"
    },
    {
        "question": "Canada is divided into provinces and what else?",
        "answer": "Territories"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Area 51?",
        "answer": "Nevada"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state name ends with three vowels?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Southern Ocean completely surrounds which continent?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Antarctica is surrounded by which ocean?",
        "answer": "Southern ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state is nicknamed `Little Rhody`?",
        "answer": "Rhode Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only African nation with Spanish as the official language?",
        "answer": "Equatorial Guinea"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city was Bruce Lee born in?",
        "answer": "San Francisco, California"
    },
    {
        "question": "Monrovia is the capital of what African country?",
        "answer": "Liberia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state that has a Spanish motto, `Oro y Plata`?",
        "answer": "Montana"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much did the United States pay Russia per acre for the purchase of Alaska in 1867?",
        "answer": "About 2 Cents per acre"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Macedonia?",
        "answer": "Skopje"
    }
]